<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1'?><?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='http://w3future.com/w3f/w3f.xsl' ?>
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2002/06/xhtml2" xmlns:ev="http://www.w3.org/2001/xml-events" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xf="http://www.w3.org/2002/xforms/cr" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://w3future.com/html/stories/hop.txt">
<head>
<title>Higher Order Programming - article</title>
</head>
<body>
<section id="content">
	<h>Higher Order Programming - article</h>
	<p>In Javascript</p>
	<section id="note">
		<h>Required knowledge</h><p>You'll have to know how to program object oriented with Javascript. Read the articles at Webreference (links at the left of the article) to catch up on that.</p><h>Last Update</h>
		<p>10/16/2005; 1:23:45 AM</p>
		<p id="alternates" class="buttons">
			<l href="http://w3future.com/html/stories/hop.xml?notransform" rel="alternate" type="application/xml" title="See this web page with XHTML 2.0 technology."><span>Try</span> XHTML 2.0</l>
			<l href="view-source:http://w3future.com/html/stories/hop.xml?notransform" title="View the XHTML 2.0 source of this page."><span>Src</span> XHTML 2.0</l>
			<l href="http://w3future.com/tools/xr.pl?xr=http://w3future.com/xr/w3f.xml&amp;xml=http://w3future.com/html/stories/hop.xml%3Fnotransform" rel="meta" type="application/rdf+xml" title="RDF metadata"><span>RDF</span> Metadata</l>
		</p>
		<xi:include href="http://w3future.com/w3f/buttons.xml" />
	</section><section>
<h>Introduction</h>
<section>
<p>Higher Order Programming is the ability to use functions as values.
So you can pass functions as arguments to other functions and
functions can be the return value of other functions.
This style of programming is mostly used in functional programming,
but it can also be very useful in 'regular' object oriented
programming. A good example of this is the Ruby Scripting Language,
which combines all the advantages of pure object oriented programming 
and higher order programming. Sadly, Ruby is not supported by
any browser, so it cannot be used for websites. We are lucky 
however that Javascript is available in every browser, and that 
Javascript is so flexible that it can be extended to make higher 
order programming a helpful tool in scripting webpages.</p>
</section>
 
<section>
<h>The <code>sort</code> method</h>
<p>Most people will know Javascript only as a scripting language
that makes image switching and annoying popup windows possible.
However the Javascript implementations hint at the more advanced
programming possibilities through the sort Method of arrays.
In it's simple form <code>sort()</code> will just sort the array:
The code <code>document.write([2,3,1,4].sort())</code> will 
write "1,2,3,4". But the sort method can do more. It allows a
compare function as an optional argument. That's higher order
programming right there. Suppose we have an array of objects.
Each object has a <code>date</code> property, and we want to
sort the objects by their date value:</p>
<blockcode>arrayOfObjects.sort(
  function (x,y) {
    return x.date-y.date;
  }
);</blockcode>
<p>The compare function is called regularly during sorting.
It must return a negative value when <code>x</code> comes
before <code>y</code>, zero when the are equal and a 
possitive value when <code>x</code> comes after <code>y</code>.
This is exactly what substraction does for numbers and dates,
for strings you can just use <code>&lt;</code> and 
<code>&gt;</code>.</p>
</section></section>
 
<section>
<h>Generating HTML</h>
<section>
<h>Using functions as arguments</h>
<p>If you have generated HTML from arrays before, this code will
look familiar:</p>
<blockcode>var s='';
for (var i=0;i&lt;arr.length;i++) {
  var item=arr[i];
  s+=<i>...generate some HTML...</i>
}
document.write(s);</blockcode>
<p>We will now create a <code>reduce</code> method, that will
make this a bit more readable, and make the code more modular.
The above code will then look like this:</p>
<blockcode>function prettyTemplate(item) {
  return <i>...generate some HTML...</i>
}
document.write(arr.reduce(prettyTemplate));</blockcode>
<p>To create the reduce method, we can use much of the previous
example. We'll extend the array prototype, so all arrays will
have the reduce method available:</p>
<blockcode>Array.prototype.reduce=function(templateFunction) {
  var l=this.length;
  var s='';
  for (var i=0;i&lt;l;i++) s+=templateFunction(this[i]);
  return s;
}</blockcode>
</section>
 
<section>
<h>Using a function as return value</h>
<p>The template function will often be simple: It will just wrap
each item in the array with one HTML element. F.e. when creating
a table, the template function won't do much more than:
<code>return '&lt;TD&gt;'+item+'&lt;/TD&gt;';</code>. Let's
create a function that generates these simple element wrappers:</p>
<blockcode>function wrap(tag) {
  var stag='&lt;'+tag+'>';
  var etag='&lt;/'+tag.replace(/s.*/,'')+'>';
  return function(x) {
    return stag+x+etag;
  }
}  
 
// examples:
 
document.write(wrap('B')('This is bold.'));
var B=wrap('B');
document.write(B('This is bold too.'));
 
document.write(
  '&lt;TABLE>&lt;TR>'+
    arr.reduce(wrap('TD class="small"'))+
  '&lt;/TR>&lt;/TABLE>'
);</blockcode>
<p>In the first example you can see that you can immediately call 
the returned function, which results in a somewhat unusual syntax
of two argument lists next to eachother.
There's another special thing happening here: the returned function
referes to the <code>stag</code> and <code>etag</code> variables.
That this works outside of the <code>wrap</code> function
is because of the closure like behaviour of
functions in Javascript. When a function is defined, it stores a
pointer to the current scope. This scope is restored when the
function is called.</p>
</section>
 
<section>
<h>Using functions as objects</h>
<p>In the last example, an array is converted to a table,
each item in the array is wrapped with a <code>&lt;TD></code> element.
If we want a vertical table layout, instead of horizontal, each item
must be wrapped with both a <code>&lt;TR></code> element and a
<code>&lt;TD></code> element. So we must create a new function again:</p>
<blockcode>var TABLE=wrap('TABLE');var TR=wrap('TR');var TD=wrap('TD');
document.write(TABLE(arr.reduce(
  function (item) {
    return TR(TD(item));
  }
)));</blockcode>
<p><code>TR(TD(item))</code> is like function composition, 
written as 'TR o TD', and pronounced as 'TR after TD'. 
So we'd like to write this as:</p>
<pre>document.write(TABLE(arr.reduce(TR.after(TD))));</pre>
<p>In Javascript functions are objects too, and they can also have 
methods. So we can extend the function prototype so that the
<code>after</code> method is available to all functions.</p>
<blockcode>Function.prototype.after=function(g) {
  var f=this;
  return function(x) {
    return f(g(x));
  }
}</blockcode>
</section></section>
 
<section>
<h>Using methods as functions</h>
<section>
<p><em>Update: Dan Shappir pointed out to me that is useful for
event handlers and callback function too. 
<a href="http://w3future.com/html/stories/callbacks.xml">Read more
about that here.</a></em></p>
<p>When doing higher order programming in an object oriented language,
you'd want to pass methods as arguments. But there's a problem.
Let's make an <code>element</code> class with a <code>wrap</code> method:</p>
<blockcode>function element(tag) {
  this.stag='&lt;'+tag+'>';
  this.etag='&lt;/'+tag.replace(/s.*/,'')+'>';
  this.wrap=function(x) {
    return this.stag+x+this.etag;
  }
}
 
P=new element('P');
// this works:
document.write(P.wrap('This is a paragraph.'));
// this fails:
document.write(arr.reduce(P.wrap));</blockcode>
<p>Why does this fail? Because when <code>P.wrap</code> is passed
to the reduce function, only the function is passed, where 
<code>this</code> has a different meaning. But there's a little
trick that makes method passing work:</p>
<blockcode>function element(tag) {
  this.stag='&lt;'+tag+'>';
  this.etag='&lt;/'+tag.replace(/s.*/,'')+'>';
  var me=this;
  this.wrap=function(x) {
    return me.stag+x+me.etag;
  }
}
 
P=new element('P');
// this still works:
document.write(P.wrap('This is a paragraph.'));
// and now this works too:
document.write(arr.reduce(P.wrap));</blockcode>
<p>It looks like it's the same, but <code>me</code> is just a variable
where <code>this</code> has a special meaning to every function.
Javascript will make sure the <code>wrap</code> method will still
know what <code>me</code> points to, no matter where the method is used.
</p>
</section></section>
 
<section>
<h>When should you use this?</h>
<section>
<h>Modularisation</h>
<p>When you have 2 (or several) functions that are almost the same 
except for a small part of the code, then you should consider to
combine these functions into one. Replace the part that is different
with a function call to a separate function. This function is passed
to the new more general function as an argument.</p>
</section>
 
<section>
<h>Something different</h>
<p>When you've grown bored of writing for-loops (like I did), 
methods like <code>reduce</code> will be a welcome change in 
programming style. For me, higher order programming has made Javascript
a lot more fun, and I hope you'll have fun with this too!</p>
</section></section><xi:include href="http://w3future.com/tools/rdf.php?about=http://w3future.com/html/stories/hop.txt" /></section>
<section id="navigation"><xi:include href="http://w3future.com/w3f/sections.xml" /></section>
<section id="sidebar"><xi:include href="http://w3future.com/weblog/sidebars/stories.opml" /></section>
</body>
</html>