<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- generator="Stapler/2.2.6" -->
<rss version="0.92">
	<channel>
		<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
		<title>Joel on Software</title>
		<description>painless software management</description>
		<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/</link>
		<managingEditor>sjoerd@w3future.com</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>sjoerd@w3future.com</webMaster>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2003 00:55:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;This week, both &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.informationweek.com/story/showArticle.jhtml?articleID=8800337&quot;&gt;InformationWeek&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.baselinemag.com/article2/0,3959,1016969,00.asp&quot;&gt;Baseline&lt;/A&gt; have feature stories about new technology at Delta Air Lines, so it&apos;s a good opportunity to benchmark Baseline, a new IT magazine from Ziff Davis, to its old school press-release republishing counterparts.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The difference: while the &lt;EM&gt;InformationWeek&lt;/EM&gt; article is just a poor rewrite of bland warmed-over press releases and vague generalizations, the Baseline article is detailed, interesting, and specific. For example Baseline noticed that Delta&apos;s new information system crashed for two hours at the worst time possible: when I was in New Orleans trying to reschedule my flight home during last month&apos;s blizzard. InformationWeek didn&apos;t mention the outage. In fact the whole Baseline article looks like it was written by an investigative journalist. It&apos;s about time the industry press got its act together.&amp;nbsp;Go for the&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.omeda.com/ziff/bsl/bsl.cgi?&amp;amp;p=homepage2&quot;&gt;free subscription&lt;/A&gt;, it&apos;s worth it.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030422.html</link>
			<title>Tuesday, April 22, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;Chandler &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.osafoundation.org/Rel_0.1_Info.htm&quot;&gt;Release 0.1&lt;/A&gt; is out. See what all the fuss is about, almost.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Larry Seltzer wants to &lt;A href=&quot;http://security.ziffdavis.com/article2/0,3973,1036052,00.asp?kc=SCZD103039TX1K0100568&quot;&gt;throw out SMTP&lt;/A&gt; and start over. I have to support that.&amp;nbsp;If the European Union can change the money that 300 million people use all on one day, we can change our email protocol. Let&apos;s find a protocol with decent authentication and with micropayments to make spam uneconomical, and let&apos;s set a deadline, maybe two years in the future, when SMTP will simply be turned off. Everybody will know it&apos;s coming, just like Y2K, and everybody will have to be ready.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;A couple of new books worth checking out:&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0932633609/ref=nosim/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0932633609/ref=nosim/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Waltzing With Bears&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: Managing Risk on Software Projects. The latest book from the heroes of &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0932633439/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;Peopleware&lt;/A&gt;, Tom Demarco and Timothy Lister. Makes a brave case that the person (or company, or team) who is responsible for risk management is the person who is going to pay the price when things go wrong. &lt;EM&gt;Waltzing With Bears &lt;/EM&gt;kicks off with an excellent analysis of the famous &quot;failure&quot; of software engineering that delayed the opening of the new Denver airport, framing it as a failure of risk management. In fact when you look a bit more closely at the software project itself, it&apos;s pretty clear that the software team was expected to perform the impossible, and the project as a whole had no way to recover from a slip in a typically over-optimistic software schedule.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0735713243/ref=nosim/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0735713243/ref=nosim/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Speed Up Your Site&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;: Web Site Optimization by Andrew King. A well written and very thorough treatise on what you can do to reduce download times and speed up web sites. Yes, putting your whole HTML page on one line can really help.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR clear=all&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0465071449/ref=nosim/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0465071449/ref=nosim/joelonsoftware&quot;&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;No-Collar&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/STRONG&gt;: The Humane Workplace and Its Hidden Costs, by Andrew Ross. A big disappointment. I think the original book was not exciting enough so the publisher tried to present it as a critique of informal, humane workplaces. The &quot;hidden cost,&quot; they want us to believe, of pleasant, diverse workplaces seems to be that they shut down and you lose your job. I know, it doesn&apos;t make any sense. The author wanted to write a book about cool dotcoms, but they all imploded, and he was stuck trying to claim that they imploded because they tried to have a humane workplace, without really believing it himself, so it comes out a big mess.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Most of the book, though, is an interesting&amp;nbsp;look inside two of the&amp;nbsp;Aeron-infested workplaces of the fin-de-si&amp;#195;&amp;#168;cle, presenting a picture of young and diverse liberal arts majors jammed in a big room together playing loud music and patting themselves on the back for having such cool unjobs. Rather than focusing on the business stories behind Razorfish and 360hiphop.com, which we&apos;ve presumably heard, this book tries to look at the work environment itself. Unfortunately it&apos;s written in a current-events American Studies tone rather than as an ethnography, which is too bad, because some anthropological skills would have made this a million times more interesting (and useful, to those of us that are trying to create humane workspaces while creating successful businesses).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030421.html</link>
			<title>Monday, April 21, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;Bob at &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.wise.com&quot;&gt;Wise Solutions&lt;/A&gt; emailed to remind me that the &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.wise.com/wis.asp&quot;&gt;Wise Installation System&lt;/A&gt; has patching built in, and costs less than InstallShield plus vBuild.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;He also pointed out that &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.wise.com/wfwi.asp&quot;&gt;Wise for Windows Installer&lt;/A&gt; now has a ton of features for server setups: user account creation, IIS administration, and SQL Server administration... basically they implemented my entire wish list from working on the FogBUGZ 3.0 installer. Good work!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Some people on the forum expressed concern with the concept of distributing upgrade patches rather than complete copies of changed files. I can see why they are concerned, but I think they are underestimating the tools that are out there. These tools check the version of each file on the user&apos;s machine and also compute a hash function to make sure that the file is not corrupted. If the file is corrupted, they automatically download the whole thing.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Using patching technology saves a lot of bandwidth, even for the first-time installer, because a lot of the bytes you&apos;re distributing may be system files and runtimes that users already have. For example, we need to redistribute things like the Microsoft C Runtime (MSVCRT) which almost everyone already has, just because there may exist a few Windows machines in the wild which don&apos;t have it. For consumer software which may well be downloaded over a modem, this makes a big difference.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;For now, Michael convinced me to stick with the tried-and-true &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.wintax.nl/isx/&quot;&gt;Inno Setup&lt;/A&gt; for the next release of CityDesk. The bandwidth savings don&apos;t quite justify the effort of switching installers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030418.html</link>
			<title>Friday, April 18, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;A question for tech writers: why does every technical manual and book include a section at the beginning on &quot;conventions used in this document,&quot; full of ridiculous and useless tips like, &quot;Tips are indicated by a lightbulb icon in the margin&quot;? Is it because you&apos;re paid by the word?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;To steal a joke from&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.mrbunny.com/mbgtax.html&quot;&gt;Mr. Bunny&apos;s Guide to ActiveX&lt;/A&gt;, I would like to announce that&amp;nbsp;&quot;the familiar dot (.)&amp;nbsp;symbol from Internet addresses shall be used on this website to denote the end of a sentence.&quot;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Incremental Installation&lt;/STRONG&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/fog0000000349.html&quot;&gt;Last year&lt;/A&gt; I was designing the&amp;nbsp;upgrade installer&amp;nbsp;for CityDesk. I was considering RTPatch but it was really expensive (disproportionate to what we would spend in bandwidth), so we just made an upgrader that reinstalls full copies of every file that had changed.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;At the time RTPatch was $5000 for a license, and their salesman called me up to give me a hard time for contradicting myself. After all, step 9 in the &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000043.html&quot;&gt;Joel Test&lt;/A&gt; is using &quot;the best tools that money can buy.&quot; &quot;Touch&amp;#195;&amp;#169;,&quot; I said, and hung up.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Now there&apos;s competition. A little Israeli company, &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.redbend.com&quot;&gt;Red Bend Software&lt;/A&gt;, has a product called vBuild, which is tightly integrated with InstallShield Professional (the non-Windows MSI version of InstallShield). vBuild is about $2500 and&amp;nbsp;RTPatch has come down to $2750. Still pricey but starting to seem worth it. Today I&apos;m going to try converting CityDesk&apos;s setup from &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.jrsoftware.org/isinfo.php&quot;&gt;InnoSetup&lt;/A&gt;, which is&amp;nbsp;excellent and free, to &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.installshield.com&quot;&gt;InstallShield&lt;/A&gt;, which is decent and expensive, just to take advantage of vBuild.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030416.html</link>
			<title>Wednesday, April 16, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;Basically, we&apos;re moving because of William Whyte&apos;s rule: virtually all corporate relocations involve a move to a location which is closer to the CEO&apos;s home than the old location. Whyte discovered this principle after an extensive study of Fortune 500 companies that left New York City for the suburbs in the 1950s and 1960s. They always had big, complicated Relocation Committees which carefully studied all the options and chose, coincidentally I&apos;m sure, to move to within half a mile of the CEO&apos;s home in Danbury, Connecticut. Whyte also showed that these companies all tanked after the relocation.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;This may be, possibly, the most off-topic article I&apos;ve ever done here. But I try to write only about things I know about, and, recently, I learned a lot more about commercial real estate than I &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/OfficeNewYork.html&quot;&gt;ever imagined I would need to know...&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Oh, good, &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.techinterview.org&quot;&gt;TechInterview&lt;/A&gt; is back!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030328.html</link>
			<title>Friday, March 28, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;Not bad: about&amp;nbsp;four hours of work to &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.leadtools.com/&quot;&gt;implement&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;a picture editor with crop, resize, rotate, undo, and save.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;It did take about four hours yesterday to figure out which OCX/DLL files I need to ship and make sure that SETUP included them, and I spent an hour last night reading the documentation to get a better idea for what I have to do.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030326.html</link>
			<title>Wednesday, March 26, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;A couple of the monthly columns I&amp;#8217;ve been doing for the &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/https://www.programmersparadise.com/secure/catalog_request.pasp?CATREQ=WEBFOGC&quot;&gt;Programmer&amp;#8217;s Paradise catalog&lt;/A&gt; are now on the web: a review of &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.programmersparadise.com/promo/JoelSoftware_0303.pasp&quot;&gt;VMWare&lt;/A&gt; and a column on&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.programmersparadise.com/promo/JoelSoftware_0403.pasp&quot;&gt;data modeling with ERwin&lt;/A&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Coming up: a&amp;nbsp;five minute introduction to user interface design, and a look at my experience using&amp;nbsp;the profiler in CompuWare&apos;s DevPartner Studio to speed up &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.fogcreek.com/CityDesk&quot;&gt;CityDesk&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;750 words doesn&apos;t give me much of a chance to really review things in depth, but I do have a policy for writing reviews: I only review products that I actually want to use&amp;nbsp;in my daily work at Fog Creek. Unlike trade magazine reviewers, I still spend about 50% of my time doing software development, and I&amp;#8217;m happy to try the latest toys if I think they will help. For example, this week I&amp;#8217;m going to try to implement a basic image editor into CityDesk using &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.leadtools.com&quot;&gt;LeadTools&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In other news, we have signed the lease for our new office space, and the architect came up with a groovy floorplan with parallelogram offices.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030324.html</link>
			<title>Monday, March 24, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I finally got around to adding bidirection text support to &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.fogcreek.com/CityDesk&quot;&gt;CityDesk&lt;/A&gt;, so today I can launch &lt;A href=&quot;http://hebrew.joelonsoftware.com&quot;&gt;Hebrew&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href=&quot;http://farsi.joelonsoftware.com&quot;&gt;Farsi&lt;/A&gt; editions of Joel on Software, bringing the total language count up to 24.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030323.html</link>
			<title>Sunday, March 23, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.angrycoder.com/article.aspx?cid=10&amp;amp;y=2003&amp;amp;m=3&amp;amp;d=13&quot;&gt;AngryCoder&lt;/A&gt;: &amp;#8220;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.fogcreek.com/FogBUGZ&quot;&gt;FogBUGZ&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;is very well designed, and virtually bug free. Frankly, if you are in the market for a defect tracking solution, you can&amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#153;t do much better than FogBUGZ. It is by far the best solution on the market right now, and is also very attractively priced.&amp;#8221; &lt;EM&gt;Thanks! &lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Joseph Jones, who wrote the review, didn&amp;#8217;t like the perceived lack of customizability in FogBUGZ. I hear ya. This was one of those &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20020912.html&quot;&gt;agonizing decisions&lt;/A&gt; for us. It&amp;#8217;s a tradeoff between implementing features that make the sale, versus implementing features that, we think, will make people who use our software love it, which helps in the long term. At the time it was &lt;A href=&quot;http://discuss.fogcreek.com/joelonsoftware/default.asp?cmd=show&amp;amp;ixPost=15389&amp;amp;ixReplies=31&quot;&gt;discussed in depth&lt;/A&gt; here on &lt;EM&gt;Joel on Software&lt;/EM&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Take, for example, a typical report a bug tracking package gives you that shows you the number of bugs generated per day per programmer. Typical bad managers will use that tool to punish programmers with high bug counts or reward programmers with low bug counts. As a result, every time a tester tries to enter a bug, the programmer will argue about it. &amp;#8220;That&apos;s not really a bug.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Please don&apos;t enter it, I&apos;ll fix it on the side for you.&amp;#8221; Eventually the bug tracking system subverts itself. That&apos;s not FogBUGZ&apos;s fault, but there you have it. Nobody wants to use it, they never upgrade, they don&apos;t buy more licenses when they get more programmers, and we lose the potential word of mouth.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The current system, in which we expect FogBUGZ users to have enlightened development processes, makes us miss out on initial sales but it makes our existing customers happier. And they tell friends, and they buy more and more licences, and all is good. We&apos;ve found that anyone who has been using FogBUGZ and moves on to a new job that doesn&apos;t have bug tracking will recommend FogBUGZ at their new job, which is one reason our sales are up by about 200% since last year.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;But this is all, to some extent, speculation. I can&apos;t prove anything here. Design decisions are hard that way.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030314.html</link>
			<title>Friday, March 14, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;I just got back from inspecting the new Fog Creek Office, a sunny loft in the &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.fashioncenter.com/&quot;&gt;shmatta district&lt;/A&gt;, with the architect. It&apos;s going to make a really nice office when we&apos;re finished building it out, with private offices, a living room area, kitchenette, and, budget permitting, a pool table and plasma TV. Here&apos;s what I told the architect:&lt;/P&gt;

private windowed offices are non-negotiable
we need three times as many power outlets as anyone would think. I&apos;m sick of power strips. I have ten things plugged in right at my desk. I specified 4 outlets every foot, is that absurd?
I want to be able to pull my own lan, telephone, fiber, and cable TV wires. Even if they&apos;re &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.snaketray.com/products/overhead.html&quot;&gt;exposed&lt;/A&gt;.
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030307.html</link>
			<title>Friday, March 7, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;My latest article, &amp;#8220;Building Communities with Software,&amp;#8221; was sent to email subscribers earlier today. &lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you did not get it and expected to get it, you&apos;re probably having problems with overenthusiastic spam filters. I got lots of bounces, mostly from Fortune 500 type companies, rejecting the message, because of &quot;inappropriate content&quot; or because their automatic filters had decided it was spam. Some of them complained about &quot;taboo,&quot; other&apos;s complained about &quot;hard core.&quot; Most didn&apos;t tell me. Such is the state of email today.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you did not get the article and you want it,&amp;nbsp;you can read a shorter,&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/BuildingCommunitieswithSo.html&quot;&gt;sanitized version&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;online. But it still contains the word &quot;taboo&quot; so if that offends you you may want to avert your eyes!&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030303.html</link>
			<title>Monday, March 3, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;The social scientist Ray Oldenburg talks about how humans need a third place, besides work and home, to meet with friends, have a beer, discuss the events of the day, and enjoy some human interaction. Coffee shops, bars, hair salons, beer gardens, pool halls, clubs, and other hangouts are as vital as factories, schools and apartments [&quot;The Great Good Place&quot;, 1989]. But capitalist society has been eroding those third places, and society is left impoverished. In &quot;Bowling Alone,&quot; Robert Putnam brings forth, in riveting and well-documented detail, reams of evidence that American society has all but lost its third places. Over the last 25 years, Americans &quot;belong to fewer organizations that meet, know our neighbors less, meet with friends less frequently, and even socialize with our families less often.&quot; [2000] For too many people, life consists of going to work, then going home and watching TV. Work-TV-Sleep-Work-TV-Sleep. It seems to me that the phenomenon is far more acute among software developers, especially in places like Silicon Valley and the suburbs of Seattle. People graduate from college, move across country to a new place where they don&apos;t know anyone, and end up working 12 hour days basically out of loneliness.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;So it&apos;s no surprise that so many programmers, desperate for a little human contact, flock to online communities - chat rooms, discussion forums, open source projects, and Ultima Online. In creating community software, we are, to some extent, trying to create a third place. And like any other architecture project, the design decisions we make are crucial. Make a bar too loud, and people won&apos;t be able to have conversations. That makes for a very different kind of place than a coffee shop. Make a coffee shop without very many chairs, as Starbucks does, and people will carry their coffee back to their lonely rooms, instead of staying around and socializing like they do in the fantasy TV coffeehouse of &quot;Friends,&quot; a program we watch because an ersatz third place is less painful than none at all. &lt;/P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;
&lt;BR clear=all&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In software, as in architecture, design decisions are just as important to the type of community that develops or fails to develop. When you make something easy, people do it more often. When you make something hard, people do it less often. In this way you can gently encourage people to behave in certain ways which determine the character and quality of the community. Will it feel friendly? Is there thick conversation, a European salon full of intellectuals with interesting ideas? Or is the place deserted, with a few dirty advertising leaflets lying around on the floor that nobody has bothered to pick up?&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;EM&gt;&amp;#8212; Excerpted from my latest article, &amp;#8220;Building Communities with Software,&amp;#8221; which will only be sent to email subscribers. Please subscribe now to receive the article, which will be sent out on Monday morning.&lt;/EM&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030228.html</link>
			<title>Friday, February 28, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;The discussion forum for this site generates a lot of questions and commentary. As I said when I launched it, it&apos;s a bit of an experiment. Although it may seem simple, there are a lot of subtle design decisions and magic-behind-the-scenes in hopes of improving the quality of discussion that takes place there. So far, it has mostly worked.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Later this week I&apos;ll write an essay explaining everything, but because it&apos;s full of Heisenberg effects, the essay won&apos;t appear on this web site, it will only go out via email to email subscribers. You can subscribe here or at the bottom of any page on my site:&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;   Email:    &lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Don&apos;t worry, you can unsubscribe at any time; every email I send includes a single-click unsubscribe link. I will never sell your email address. Subscribe by Friday to be sure to get the essay. Once again -- the essay will not appear on the web and will be copyright so I&apos;ll ask you not to forward the email around. It&apos;s an exclusive benefit for email subscribers.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030225.html</link>
			<title>Tuesday, February 25, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;Due to the poor sound quality of the previous &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.paxlogica.com/cdFull.html&quot;&gt;CityDesk online demo&lt;/A&gt;, I decided to invest in a real studio quality microphone instead of using one of those cheap computer headset/mike combinations.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;It took me a while to figure out what I needed. The mike itself is a &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.shure.com/microphones/models/sm58.asp&quot;&gt;Shure SM58&lt;/A&gt;, probably one of the most popular professional microphones in use today and generally available for about $100. &lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I bought the Mic from &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.samashmusic.com&quot;&gt;Sam Ash&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;on 48th street, hoping that they would be able to get me the right combination of cables and adapters I needed to plug this thing into a standard sound card. The stoner DJ sales dude sounded very confident but he didn&apos;t tell me that I needed a preamp, and he gave me the wrong kind of cables.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;If you&apos;re trying to do this yourself, here&apos;s exactly what I have:&lt;/P&gt;

the&amp;nbsp;Shure SM58 microphone 
A basic desk stand. The clip part that connects the mike to the stand comes with the mike. 
a 3&apos; mic cable (it only needs to reach the preamp). I bought a CBI LowZ Microphone Cable from &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.zzounds.com&quot;&gt;Zzounds&lt;/A&gt;. 
A preamp. This boosts the level of the microphone to something that is called &quot;Line Level&quot; which is what a computer sound card needs. I got an &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.m-audio.com/products/m-audio/audibudy.php&quot;&gt;M-Audio AudioBuddy&lt;/A&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Zzounds. 
To connect the preamp to the sound card, you need a cable with a 1/4&quot; stereo phone jack on one end and a 1/8&quot; stereo &quot;mini&quot; phone jack on the other end. I assembled this out of two cables which I bought at my neighborhood Radio Shack. For some reason the professional music stores like Sam Ash and Zzounds think it is beneath their dignity to stock any parts with 1/8&quot; jacks, but that is what your sound card needs.
&lt;P&gt;The sound quality is really quite a bit better. Here are two MP3s, &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/pictures/cheapmic.mp3&quot;&gt;before&lt;/A&gt; (with the computer mike) and &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/pictures/expensivemic.mp3&quot;&gt;after&lt;/A&gt; (with the professional mike).&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030214.html</link>
			<title>Friday, February 14, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Dave &lt;A href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/backissues/2003/02/04#When:2:49:44PM&quot;&gt;asks&lt;/A&gt;: &quot;When I get Slashdotted we get about 5000 reads. I&apos;ve noticed that number is about what some Manila and Radio sites have gotten when they were Slashdotted. Now, according to Joel Spolsky he gets about 400,000 reads from a Slashdot link, about 80 times the flow. Now here&apos;s the question. Why?&quot;
&lt;P&gt;Actually, I said 500,000, not 400,000, and I was referring to &lt;EM&gt;hits&lt;/EM&gt;, not &quot;reads.&quot; I&apos;m not sure what a read is, but a hit is a single file served by the web server. Even the simplest page on this site consists of four files: the header GIF, the Made with CityDesk GIF, the CityDesk logo, and the article itself. Articles with pictures have a lot more. The number of page views we get, which only counts HTML files, is about 120,000 on &quot;slashdot days.&quot; Since the average day has about 30,000 page views, only 90,000 are &quot;extra.&quot; Still a lot more than Manila sites, but not 80 times the flow.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Another difference is that I almost always get slashdotted on a day when I release a new article. This is coincidentally the same day I send email to 16,000 subscribers telling them about the new article. And on average a few dozen webloggers will link to me on the same day, bringing in their traffic as well.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Some percentage of those people say, &quot;Aha! This precisely proves my point!&quot; and forward the URL to their boss or underling to hit them over the head with it. &quot;See? Nya!&quot; So there&apos;s always a multiplier effect.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Finally, Joel on Software has enough old content that many new visitors stay a while and click around. That accounts for a lot of the extra traffic on Slashdot days.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030205.html</link>
			<title>Wednesday, February 5, 2003</title>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;I&apos;ve moved &lt;EM&gt;Joel on Software&lt;/EM&gt; to a new server, at a colocation facility operated by &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.peer1.net&quot;&gt;Peer 1 Network&lt;/A&gt;. In the process of finding a new home and getting it up and running I&apos;ve learned quite a bit about how web hosting works, so I thought I&apos;d describe a bit of it here and in the process provide a glimpse &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/Peer1.html&quot;&gt;Behind The Scenes&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;</description>
			<link>http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20030204.html</link>
			<title>Tuesday, February 4, 2003</title>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
